Athénaïs **Gautier**, Ph.D.

- About me -

Soon to be PhD in statistics, and passionate about applying machine learning to solve real-world problems.

My skills in mathematics, statistics and programming will be an asset when faced with technical challenges. My experience in research and teaching allows me to communicate my results clearly and effectively. I look forward to working whithin a stimulating environment!

Contact information -

■ athenais.gautier@unibe.ch

https://athenaisgautier.github.io/

+33647721875

- Languages -

French - Native Language

👭 English - Fluent

Professional Skills

Jupyter Notebooks Python **ETEX**

Soft Skills and Strengths

Creativity Problem solving Open minded **Team Working** Love Learning New Things Good communication

Other Interests

- Aerial sports
- Crafting
- · Baking, cooking
- · Train travels

(E) WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov. 2018 -**Today**

Research and teaching assistant **Q** Bern, Switzerland Institute of statistics, University of Bern

Until May 2020, the affiliation was shared with Idiap Research Institute (Martigny, Switzerland).

Research assistant with a strong focus on the Ph.D. topic. Active participation in scientific collaborations, proficiency in coding and creating reproducible examples using R language. Main research interests: Uncertainty Quantification, Gaussian Processes, Bayesian Optimization, Bayesian Statistics, Computer simulation models.

Senior consultant of the institute of statistics, University of Bern. Helping academics and companies planning and conducting statistical analysis (Jan. 2021 - Dec. 2023)

Teaching assistant at various levels:

- ♦ For the institute of statistics at University of Bern for several course at Bachelor and Master level. (Jan. 2019 - ongoing)
- ♦ In statistics, for the first the continuing education Master of AI in Switzerland; a collaboration between Idiap Research Institute and Unidistance (Jan. 2019 - May 2020).
- ♦ Co-supervisor (main supervisor: D. Ginsbourger) of the Master thesis "Gaussian process regression on molecules: some performance assessments and comparisons". (2021).

March. 2018

- Oct. 2018

Research Intern *Idiap Research Institute*

Optimisation and sensitivity analysis within the "Statistical and machine learning approaches to optimization problems under uncertainty arising in energy planning" collaboration with

June 2017 -Aug. 2017

Engineering intern

ELM Leblanc

CREM.

Working on data integration within energetic systems: identifying exploitable data, possible applications and inherent risks.

EDUCATION

Nov. 2018 -**Ongoing**

Ph.D. in Statistics

9 Bern, Switzerland

♀ Drancy, France

♀ Martigny, Switzerland

University of Bern

Until May 2020, the affiliation was shared with Idiap Research Institute (Martigny, Switzerland).

Working on the topic: "Modelling and predicting distributionvalued fields with applications to inversion under uncertainty" under supervision of Pr. David Ginsbourger.

Expected graduation May 2023.

Sept. 2017 -Oct. 2018

Master in Applied Mathematics

Paris, France

University Paris Dauphine

Major in statistical and financial engineering, specialising in statistics.

Obtained with first grade honors and ranked top student of the

Sept. 2015 -

Sept. 2018

Master in Engineering

♀ Saint-Etienne, France

École des Mines de Saint-Etienne

School ranked 14th out of the 140 french engineering schools by the Times Higher Education World University Ranking Majoring in statistics and data science.

Ranked in the top 10% of students in these specialities.

Sept. 2013 -**July 2015**

Preparatory classes

? Paris, France

Lycée Henri IV

Intensive studies in mathematics and physics, major in mathematics and physics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Mathematics and statistics	Very strong skills acquired during studies and used to communicating and teaching to people
	of various levels of expertise.
Data analysis	Very strong theoretical and practical knowledge, advanced proficiency in ${\bf R}$, basic in ${\bf Python}$.
	Confident in the ability to progress and master other languages, currently learning Python .
Data visualization	Mastery and strong personal affinity with the subject, particularly with the ggplot2 package in
	R. Confident in the ability to transfer knowledge to other contexts.
Results presentation	Accustomed to developing and presenting reproducible examples via reports written in LaTeX,
	RMarkdown or Jupyter Notebook.

PUBLICATIONS

 $\textbf{Ph.D. thesis} \qquad \textbf{Modelling and predicting distribution-valued fields with applications to inversion under uncertainty, \underline{A.G.}, \\$

 $\textbf{Journal} \qquad \textbf{Continuous logistic Gaussian random measure fields for spatial distributional modelling,} \underline{\textbf{A.G.}}, \textbf{D.} \ \textbf{Ginsbourger}, \ \textbf{Sub-logistic Gaussian random measure fields for spatial distributional modelling}, \ \underline{\textbf{A.G.}}, \ \textbf{D.} \ \textbf{Ginsbourger}, \ \textbf{Sub-logistic Gaussian random measure fields for spatial distributional modelling}, \ \underline{\textbf{A.G.}}, \ \textbf{D.} \ \textbf{Ginsbourger}, \ \textbf{Sub-logistic Gaussian random measure fields}, \ \underline{\textbf{Continuous logistic Gaussian random measure fields}}, \ \underline{\textbf{Continuous logistic Gaussian rand$

mitted

Proceedings Goal-oriented adaptive sampling under random field modelling of response probability distributions, A.G., D. Gins-

bourger and G. Pirot, Published in ESAIM: Proceedings and Surveys.

Workshop Probabilistic ABC with Spatial Logistic Gaussian Process, A.G., D. Ginsbourger and G. Pirot, In Third Workshop on

Machine Learning and the Physical Sciences, NeurIPS 2020.

★ AWARDS AND GRANTS

Best student oral presentation: GdR MASCOT-NUM annual meeting.	
• Maximum grant: University of Bern, Fund for the Promotion of Young Researchers.	2022
Student Travel Award: SIAM Conference on Uncertainty Quantificationm	2022
Best student poster: GdR MASCOT-NUM annual meeting	2021
• Louis Neltner Excellence Scholarship awarded by the foundation of the Ecole des Mines de Saint-Etienne.	2016
• Excellence scholarship awarded by Fondation Odon Vallet on the basis of good academic results.	
• Merit scholarship awarded by the French State on the basis of excellent results in the Baccalauréat.	

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Active member of the organization committees of the events:

• Lifting Inference with Kernel Embeddings 2023 (webmaster)

June 26-30 2023

• Current frontiers in Gaussian Processes (main organizer)

Aug. 24-26, 2022

• Lifting Inference with Kernel Embeddings 2022 (webmaster)

Jan. 10-14, 2022

Academic peer review for the following structures:

• Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS) in 2022 and 2023

• Workshop: Machine Learning and the Physical Sciences at NeurIPS in 2021 and 2022

• Workshop: Synergy of Scientific and Machine Learning Modeling at ICML in 2023